vicroads.vic.gov.au 2005-06-18

# Privacy Statement

|  |  | 

****VicRoads Website Privacy Statement** **

**This statement sets out our policy in relation to your privacy and our website services.**

VicRoads is committed to protecting your privacy. Any personal information collected, handled, stored or disclosed about you through our on-line services shall be managed in accordance with the Road Safety Act 1986, Information Privacy Act 2000 and the Health Records Act 2001.Personal information means information or an opinion that is recorded about an individual whose identify is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained, from the information or opinion.

**Anonymity**

You can access our website without disclosing your personal information. However, certain functions within our website, such as change of address, feedback or the ordering of material from the on-line bookshop may require the disclosure of personal information.

**Collection and use of Personal information**

We only collect and record personal information that is provided directly to us that is necessary for us to perform our functions or activities. Personal information is collected for example in the following situations:   

  * when you send us an email;   

  * when you use our on-line services, such as completing a form electronically or paying fees online;  

  * when you register as a site user;  

  * when you provide feedback. 

**When you send us an e-mail** Your e-mail address will be recorded and used solely for the purpose for which you have provided it. It will not be disclosed, added to a mailing list or used for any other purpose without your consent. 

**When you use our on-line services, such as completing a form electronically or paying fees on-line.**

Our on-line services are managed by a service provider. Our service provider may access the personal information entered in these forms in order to process electronic transactions or to resolve a technical problem. 

**When you register as a site user**

If you register as a user of the following on-line services:   

  * Vehicle Securities Register
  * Written-off Register
  * Vehicle Registration – Dealer on-line
  * Vehicle Information Package
  * Driver and Licence Status
  * Fleet Registration Scheme

you can download the relevant **User Application Form** from the on-line services page **above** , complete, sign and forward as directed. The form outlines the user responsibility, authorisation and the meaning of confidentiality. To protect your own privacy, all passwords are to be kept confidential, and must not be displayed, shared or written down.

**Technical Information**

We collect technical information through the usage of click stream data for statistical purposes. Cookies are used to understand site usage and usability, but, we do not use web beacons.  

  * **Click stream data**

When you visit our on-line services, VicRoads makes a record of your visit. The following information, referred to as 'click stream data' in computer language, is logged by our server:   

  * your server address;   

  * your top level domain name (for example, .com, .gov, .au, .uk, etc);   

  * the date and time you visited our website or completed the on-line transaction;   

  * the pages you accessed and documents you downloaded;   

  * the type of browser you are using; and   

  * the address of the referring site (that is, the previous site you visited).  

All of this information is collected for statistical purposes to enable us to assess the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, determine what information is most and least used and help us make our site more useful to visitors. We do not actively seek to identify you. However, in the unlikely event of an investigation, a law enforcement agency may exercise a warrant to inspect our server's logs.  

  * **Use of Cookies**

When you visit our site, our server may generate a cookie. A cookie is a small piece of information (a text file) that a web server can place temporarily on your hard drive or web browser. It is used by your browser to identify the pages that you have visited on our site.   
A cookie is uniquely yours and can only be read by the server that gave it to you.   

  * **Why are Cookies used?**

We use cookies to understand site usage and to improve the content and usability of our sites. We do not use cookies to collect personal information. Cookies, alone, do not reveal your e-mail address or other personal information. You choose to provide this information by, for example, registering at our site. The information you provide may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.  

  * **Use of Web Beacons**

Our site does not currently use Web Beacons.   

  * **What is a Web Beacon?**

A web beacon is an often-transparent graphic image that is placed on a site (or in an e-mail) and when used in combination with cookies, can monitor the behaviour of the user visiting the site (or sending the e-mail). The type of information collected might include the Internet Protocol address of the computer that retrieved the image, the time the web beacon was viewed and for how long, the type of browser that retrieved the image and previously set cookie values.

_Web beacons are also known as Web bugs, pixel tags or clear GIFs._

**Security of electronic transmissions**

We take reasonable steps to secure the information transmitted to our on-line services. However, the nature of electronic transmissions is such that there is the possibility that a third party may observe this information whilst it is in transit. You may prefer to provide information by telephone or paper mail or in person.

**External Links**

When accessing external links provided on our site, it is recommended that you read the site-owners’ privacy statement before disclosing your personal information. We do not accept responsibility for inappropriate use, collection, storage or disclosure of your personal information outside of our site. 

**Access and correction**

If you:

  * want to have access to the personal information (if any) that we hold about you;  

  * want to know more about what sort of information we hold, for what purposes and how we deal with that information; or  

  * have concerns about your privacy rights, please contact us.

**How to Contact Us**

The Information Privacy Co-ordinator  
Level 5, 60 Denmark Street  
Kew, Victoria 3101  
Telephone: 13 11 71To access our **General Privacy Policy** please access this document via the attached .pdf file below -  
  
(.pdf 37Kb) /6A4E4BDB6BCED8F4CA256E9E00216997)   
Last updated on 23/12/2004 |
